A Guide to the Cleopatra White Armstrong Papers, 1923-1993
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Cleopatra White Armstrong Papers, 1923-1993
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
1996-74
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
Cleopatra White Armstrong was a native of Ellewood, Kansas. She received her public school education in St. Joseph Missouri and earned her B.S. Degree in Home Economics from the University of Nebraska in 1926. Upon completing her undergraduate degree in 1926 Ms. White (later Mrs. Armstrong) joined the faculty of The Virginia Normal and Industrial Institute in Petersburg, Virginia as a member of the Domestic Arts Department. After joining the faculty Mrs. Armstrong began working toward a graduate degree, which she earned M.S Degree in Home Economics Education from Columbia University.
Mrs. Armstrong began her career at Virginia State University as an Instructor of Domestic Art. During her teaching career which spanned fifty-one years (1926-1971) she was professor of: foods, art, textiles and clothes.
Mrs. Armstrong was very active in the community and campus organizations. Some of her affiliation's were The American Home Economics Association, The Virginia Home Economics Association, Kappa Omicron Phi which is the National Home Economics Honor Society, The Petersburg, Colonial Heights and Prince George Teachers Association, The Virginia Teachers Association, The Tri City University Women, Petersburg Chapter of the NAACP, Delta Sigma Theta Sorority Inc, and The Links Petersburg Chapter, Petersburg Chapter of Pinochle Bugs, The Holidays Inc, and the Sunday Night Supper Club. Mrs. Armstrong was the widow of Mr. Hughue M. Armstrong a Virginia State University Alumnus.
Scope and Content Information
Mostly printed material and some books showing some of Mrs. Armstrong's interests. Of special note is Mrs. Armstrong's scrapbook, which she maintained beginning in 1921. The scrapbook has several interesting items including a ticket to the Chesterfield County Colored Fair. The Cleopatra Armstrong papers reflect a life that helped so many in the field of Home Economics at Virginia state University and the many organizations that Mrs. Armstrong remained active in until her death in 1993.
Organization
SERIES I. ARTIFACTS
Artifacts from Mrs. Cleopatra Armstrong's undergraduate years at the University of Nebraska and her graduate years at Columbia University and many social organization and memorabilia. Also included in this series are newsletters, articles and numerous awards given to Mrs. Armstrong.
SERIES II. PRINTED
Obituary, newspapers, yearbooks, scrap books, and memory books, from her high school days in St. Joseph Missouri, and her days serving on the faculty of Virginia State University. There are a small number of letters and postcards in the Memory Book.
SERIES III. PHOTOGRAPHS
Photographs of Virginia State University Home Economics Department, Fashion shows, Dinner Receptions, Virginia State University Homecoming Parade, Gandy Hall children and photo's of Mrs. Cleopatra White-Armstrong.
Contents List
- SERIES I. ARTIFACTS
  - Awards 1923, 1993 (Box-folder 1:1)
- SERIES II. PRINTED
  - Newspaper clippings 1954, 1962 (Box-folder 2:2)
- SERIES III. PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Photographs 1962 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Photographs 1963 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Photographs 1964 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Photographs 1967 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Photographs 1968 (A) (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Photographs 1968 (B) (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Photographs 1969 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Photographs 1970 (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Photographs 1971 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 3:12)
  - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 3:13)
  - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 3:14)